appiancloud.com 2018-06-26

# Privacy Information | Appian BPM

## Information Collected

Appian Corporation and its subsidiaries (together, “Appian”) respect the privacy of visitors to its websites, as a result, we have developed this Internet Privacy Policy. This Internet Privacy Policy applies only to the operation of websites that directly link to this Policy when you click on “Privacy Policy” in the website footer. Through this website Appian will collect information that can identify you, such as your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, job title, and other similar information (“Your Information”) when it is voluntarily submitted to us. Any other information transferred by you in connection with your visit to this site (“Other Information” – that is, information that cannot be used to identify you) may be included in databases owned and maintained by Appian or its agents. Appian retains all rights to these databases and the information contained in them. Other Information we collect may include your IP Address and other information gathered through our weblogs and cookies (see below).  You should be aware that our websites are not intended for, or designed to attract, individuals under the age of 18. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is an individual under the age of 18.

## Use of Information

We will use Your Information to respond to requests you may make of us.  We may also use Your Information to contact you and/or provide you with general information about our products, services, partners, promotions and events. We may use the information collected to better improve our websites, products and services. We may also enhance or merge Your Information with data obtained from third parties for the same purposes.

Appian does not share, sell, rent, or trade personally identifiable information with third parties for their promotional purposes.  Appian may share information with other companies that work on Appian’s behalf or that partner with Appian. Appian will share personal information to meet any applicable law, regulation or lawful request by public authorities, including for national security or law enforcement requirements.

Appian’s policy is to restrict affiliates, subsidiaries, agents, contractors or partners from using shared information in any way other than to provide services for Appian, or services for the collaboration in which they and Appian are engaged. If we transfer personal information received under the Privacy Shield to a third party, the third party’s access, use, and disclosure of the personal data must also be in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations, and we will remain liable under the Privacy Shield for any failure to do so by the third party unless we prove we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

## Our Website Technology

**Cookies:  **Our websites may use a technology called a “cookie”. A cookie is a piece of information that our webserver sends to your computer (actually to your browser file) when you access a website. Then when you come back our site will detect whether you have one of our cookies on your computer. Our cookies help provide additional functionality to the site and help us analyze site usage more accurately. For instance, our site may set a cookie on your browser that keeps you from needing to remember and then enter a password more than once during a visit to the site. We allow carefully selected third parties to place cookies via our website. These cookies track your use of our website by collecting anonymous statistics. We do not have access to or control over these cookies or other means of passive data collection. If you are based in the European Union you can learn more about how third parties use these types of cookies by visiting [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). If you are based in the United States, please visit [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/). You do not have to accept all cookies used by our website; however, depending on the particular cookie you reject, you may not be able to use some of the features of the website. Depending on the type of browser you are using, your browser’s default settings may allow all cookies to be set. Your browser may also be configured to alert you to any cookies it comes across and/or it may allow all cookies to be set. To change your web browser settings for cookies, follow the instructions in the help section of your web browser (or please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)).  **To check your cookie settings for the Appian website,  [click here](https://www.appian.com/privacy/cookie-preferences/).**

**IP Addresses:  **Our websites use Internet Protocol (IP) Addresses. An IP Address is a number assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider so you can access the Internet. Generally, an IP address changes each time you connect to the Internet (it is a “dynamic” address). Note, however, that if you have a broadband connection, depending on your individual circumstance, it is possible that your IP Address that we collect, or even perhaps a cookie we use, may contain information that could be deemed identifiable. This is because with some broadband connections your IP Address doesn’t change (it is “static”) and could be associated with your personal computer. We use your IP address to report aggregate information on use and to help improve our websites.

**Web Beacons:**  Our websites may use a technology known as web beacons – sometimes called single-pixel gifs – that allow this site to collect web log information. A web beacon is a graphic on a web page or in an e-mail message designed to track pages viewed or messages opened. Web log information is gathered when you visit one of our websites by the computer that hosts our website (called a “webserver”). The webserver automatically recognizes some non-personal information, such as the date and time you visited our site, the pages you visited, the website you came from, the type of browser you are using (e.g., Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows 7), and the domain name and address of your Internet service provider. We may also include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages in order to determine whether messages have been opened.

**Encryption:  **Areas of our websites that collect Your Information use industry standard secure socket layer encryption (SSL); however, to take advantage of this your browser must support encryption protection (found in Internet Explorer release 3.0 and above).

**Security:  **We use reasonable physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

## Communication Preferences

Every marketing email from Appian includes information on how to opt out of receiving future marketing emails and an “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of the email.  Another way to be removed from our contact lists is to contact Appian using the Contact Information displayed below.  You may also remove yourself from our distribution list by sending a request [info@appian.com](mailto:info@appian.com). Please note that you may continue to receive materials while we are updating our lists. You may amend the information received from Appian or opt out of communications at any time by going to <https://go.pardot.com/emailPreference/e/10342/1346>.

## International Transfers

If you submit your name and email address on our website, it will be transferred, stored and processed in the United States, outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) in accordance with this privacy policy. Appian exchanges information, including personal information, between various subsidiary companies and their operations, worldwide, all as necessary to provide the services requested from Appian by its customers or for general administrative purposes. Appian may also use facilities or contractors worldwide to process or back-up information or to provide certain services to Appian.

Appian and all of its affiliated entities comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Appian has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Additionally, Appian can also offer customers and partners a data processing addendum containing the E.U. model clauses upon request.

Appian’s policy is to require our third party providers to either subscribe to the Privacy Shield Principals, be subject to the EU Privacy Directive or another adequacy finding, or enter into a written agreement that requires them to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the EU Privacy Directive, including the so-called “Model Clauses”.

## Access and Requests Regarding Your Personal Information

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Appian commits to provide you reasonable access to your personal information, the option to control Appian’s use and disclosure of your information when it is within our sole power to do so, and to resolve any complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU, Swiss and any other individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding their personal information and/or our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Appian at:

Cathy Lazarus  

At any time you may request a summary of the information Appian has about you by emailing [GDPR.Requests@appian.com](mailto:GDPR.Requests@appian.com).

Appian commits to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) and comply with the advice given by the applicable panel with regard to both personal data and human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland. Additionally, the Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Appian’s compliance with the Privacy Shield. Finally, each individual has the possibility, under certain conditions, to invoke binding arbitration for complaints regarding Privacy Shield compliance not resolved by any of the other Privacy Shield mechanisms.  This link to Annex I contains additional information about this: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.

**GDPR Information – For Our European Union Visitors and Customers**

For the purpose of GDPR, the data controller of your personal data disclosed via the Appian website for marketing and informational purposes is Appian Corporation of 11955 Democracy Drive, Reston, VA 20190.  Our GDPR contact in the United States is Cathy Lazarus ([cathy.lazarus@appian.com](mailto:cathy.lazarus@appian.com)) and located in Switzerland our GDPR contact is Caroline Johnson ([caroline.johnson@appian.com](mailto:caroline.johnson@appian.com)).

Appian does not solicit, does not require and you should not disclose to Appian any sensitive personal data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) via our website.

We will only process your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. We need certain personal data in order to provide you with access to the information you request on our website. If you have requested information be downloaded or send from this website or registered with us, you will have been asked to check a tick box indicating your agreement to provide this data in order to for such purposes. This consent provides us with the legal basis we require under applicable law to process your data. You maintain the right to withdraw such consent at any time. If you do not agree to our use of your personal data in line with this policy, please do not give us your personal data via this website.

Your data, including personal data that we collect from you, may be transferred to, stored at and processed by us and our affiliates and other third parties outside the country in which you reside, including, but not limited to the United States, where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world. By providing your personal data and confirming your consent via our website, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.

We will only retain your personal data for marketing purposes during the period of time we retain your consent unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (for example for regulatory purposes.  We will request continued consent to retain your data on an annual rolling period.

We do not use your personal data for the purposes of automated decision-making.

Opt-out.  You may contact us anytime to opt-out of: (i) direct marketing communications; (ii) our collection of sensitive personal data; (iii) any new processing of your personal data that we may carry out beyond the original purpose; or (iv) the transfer of your personal data outside the EEA. Please note that your use of some of the website and ability to receive additional information may be ineffective upon opt-out.

**Your rights:**

  * You may access the data we hold about you at any time [via your profile/account] or by contacting us directly.
  * You can also contact us to update or correct any inaccuracies in your personal data.
  * In certain situations, for example when the data we hold about you is no longer relevant or is incorrect, you can request that we erase your data.
  * While you have the right under GDPR to request your data be moved, Appian does not provide direct services to you with the personal data you disclose via this website that would require such data be moved to another third party by Appian, to continue to receive any such services.
  * You may contact us at GDPR.requests@appian.com or at the address listed below anytime for any other questions you may have about your personal data and our use of such personal data.

## Third Party Links, Message Boards

As a convenience to our visitors, our websites currently contain links to a number of sites that we believe may offer useful information. The Policies and procedures we described here do not apply to those sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection, and distribution policies. We may also make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups available to you. Please understand that any information you disclose in such areas becomes public information. We have no control over its use and encourage you to exercise caution when deciding what information to share. These sites and message board, chat rooms and forums are not intended for, or designed to attract, individuals under the age of 18.

## Enforcement, Modifications and How to contact us

Enforcement:  We regularly review our compliance with this Website Privacy Policy and encourage you to notify us of any concerns regarding our compliance with this Website Privacy Policy.

Modifications:  We may amend this Website Privacy Policy at any time and without notice, simply by posting a modification on the Site. Any modification will be effective immediately upon posting to the Site. Accordingly, please check this part of the Site from time to time to see if there has been a change.

Appian will take reasonable steps to ensure the accuracy and completeness of the personal information Appian holds. However, if a person believes that any personal information that Appian holds about them is inaccurate or out of date, they should contact Appian in writing at the following address:

Appian Corporation  
Attention: Legal Department  
11955 Democracy Drive, Suite 1700  
Reston, Virginia 20190 (USA)

**Effective date: May 8, 2018**
